{
  "passage": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "text": "Botanically, a fruit is an organ of a plant that contains and protects the seeds of the plant as they grow and often helps them to be dispersed. This broad definition of fruit includes not only produce like apples, oranges, and grapes, but also many vegetables like tomatoes and cucumbers as well as the pods of legumes and the hulls of grain. Fruits are classified in many ways, but the simplest distinction is made between fleshy fruits and dry fruits. Fleshy fruits are composed of moisture-rich cells and they are often sweet and juicy, although there are exceptions like oil-rich olives and avocados. Conversely, dry fruits are composed of dry, dead cells and are generally not edible although the seeds they contain often are. Dry fruits are further divided into two categories; those that split open when they are ripe and those that do not. Within these three broad categories, there are many subcategories of specialized fruit types."
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "text": "Regardless of their categorization, all fruits began their existence as flowers. Flowers play a central role in the life cycle of most plants as they contain reproductive structures. The majority of flowering plants produce \"perfect\" flowers that are hermaphroditic-they contain both male and female reproductive structures. Other plants produce \"imperfect\" flowers that contain either male or female structures. When a plant species produces imperfect flowers, it may produce both distinctly male and female flowers on the same individual plant, or different plants will be exclusively male or exclusively female."
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "text": "The female structures of a flower are found in the pistil at the center, which includes the ovary at the base, the long stalk called a style that grows up from the ovary, and the stigma at the top of the style. Surrounding the pistil are the male structures called stamens. They are thin stalks with pollen producing anthers at their tops. In order for a plant to reproduce, pollen must be moved from the anthers to the stigma. The transfer of pollen between the two structures is usually accomplished via organisms that visit the flower, like bees, or by the wind. Once pollen reaches the stigma, it travels down the style to the ovary, where it fertilizes an ovule. With imperfect flowers, the transfer must take place between different flowers, but perfect flowers may be fertilized by their own pollen or pollen from other flowers. Once a flower is fertilized, its future seeds begin to form, and the ovary begins to grow into a protective fruit."
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "text": "Flowers share the same basic internal structure, but their subtle differences cause them to produce very different fruit. Fleshy fruits typically fall into one of four categories. Drupes such as peaches have a single seed with an extremely hard shell called a stone that is surrounded by a thick layer of flesh. Berries such as tomatoes have many seeds without a protective stone. ® Aggregate fruits such as raspberries develop from a flower with many pistils that fuse into a dense cluster of smaller fruits. ® Multiple fruits such as pineapples are formed by the fusion of several grouped flowers that eventually merge into one fruit. ® For example, a strawberry is called an accessory fruit because the juicy portion that is eaten is actually a part of the stem, while the genuine fruits are the small seeds that dot its surface. ® "
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "text": "The fruits that farmers raise today are vastly different from the original wild plants as thousands of years of selective breeding have substantially altered their size, sweetness, and nutritional value. Scientists have found samples of maize in Central and South America that revealed the original plants look much like modern grass with a single row of small seeds on the stalk, unlike the corn cobs grown today. Paintings from centuries ago have shown that many fleshy fruits are quite different today as well. For example, a 400 year old still-life painting of fruit shows that watermelons used to be mostly bitter rind with pockets of edible red flesh around large seeds deep inside, while modern watermelons are predominately juicy red flesh and some are nearly seedless."
    }
  ],
  "questions": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "type": "single-choice",
      "data-paragraphs": [
        1
      ],
      "question": "According to paragraph 1, what is true of seeds that are present in dry fruits?",
      "choices": [
        "A. They are divided into two types based on the fruit they are present in.",
        "B. They are mostly suitable for human consumption.",
        "C. They are made up of moisture-rich cells.",
        "D. They are typically present inside pods and hulls."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "A"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "type": "single-choice",
      "data-paragraphs": [
        2
      ],
      "question": "According to paragraph 2, which of the following is possible in plants that produce imperfect flowers but not in those that produce perfect flowers?",
      "choices": [
        "A. Presence of both sexes in a single flower",
        "B. Presence of only male flowers",
        "C. Presence of both male and female reproductive structures",
        "D. Production of fruit with seeds"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "B"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "type": "single-choice",
      "data-paragraphs": [
        3
      ],
      "question": "According to paragraph 3, which of the following are mentioned as parts of the female reproductive structures of flowers?",
      "choices": [
        "A. stamens and anthers",
        "B. stigma and ovary",
        "C. stigma and anthers",
        "D. pistil and stamens"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "B"
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "type": "vocabulary",
      "data-paragraphs": [
        3
      ],
      "question": "The word \"accomplished\" in the passage is closest in meaning to",
      "choices": [
        "A. Initiated",
        "B. Supported",
        "C. Achieved",
        "D. Disrupted"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "C"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "type": "single-choice",
      "data-paragraphs": [
        3
      ],
      "question": "According to paragraph 3, one advantage perfect flowers have over imperfect flowers is that",
      "choices": [
        "A. They do not need pollen from other flowers to reproduce.",
        "B. They can reproduce without the help of bees or the wind.",
        "C. They are structured so that it is easier for the pollen to reach the stigma.",
        "D. They are able to produce seeds faster than imperfect flowers"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "A"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "type": "single-choice",
      "data-paragraphs": [
        4
      ],
      "question": "What is the author's primary purpose in paragraph 4?",
      "choices": [
        "A. To compare genuine fruits with accessory fruits",
        "B. To point out the strengths and weaknesses of different fruit structures",
        "C. To show the importance of fruit structures in plant reproduction",
        "D. To illustrate how different flower structures produce different fruits"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "D"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "type": "single-choice",
      "data-paragraphs": [
        5
      ],
      "question": "Which of the sentences below best expresses the essential information in the highlighted sentence in paragraph 5? Incorrect choices change the meaning in important ways or leave out essential information.",
      "choices": [
        "A. The fruits that we eat today are very different from the original wild plants in their size, taste, and nutritional value.",
        "B. Modern fruits are bigger, tastier, and have more nutritional value than the original wild plants because of the constant effort put into selectively breeding plants.",
        "C. A long period of selective breeding has caused significant variation in the size, taste, and nutritional value between modern fruits and early plants.",
        "D. Selective breeding led to the extinction of wild original plants and caused new types of plants with better fruits to emerge."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "C"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "type": "single-choice",
      "data-paragraphs": [
        5
      ],
      "question": "It can be inferred from paragraph 5 that compared to the original plants, modern maize",
      "choices": [
        "A. Is much larger.",
        "B. Has a brighter color.",
        "C. Looks a lot more like grass.",
        "D. Has fewer seeds."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "A"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "type": "paste missing sentence",
      "data-paragraphs": [
        4
      ],
      "question": "Look at the four squares [®] that indicate where the following sentence can be added to the passage. Some fleshy fruits do not fit into any of these categories because the portion of the plant that people eat is not the ovary. Where would the sentence best fit?",
      "choices": [
        "A. After the first [®]",
        "B. After the second [®]",
        "C. After the third [®]",
        "D. After the fourth [®]"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "D"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "type": "multiple-choice-summary",
      "data-paragraphs": [
        1,
        2,
        3,
        4,
        5
      ],
      "question": "Directions: An introductory sentence for a brief summary of the passage is provided below. Complete the summary by selecting the THREE answer choices that express the most important ideas in the passage. Some sentences do not belong in the summary because they express ideas that are not presented in the passage or are minor details in the passage. Drag and drop your answer choices to the space below. Click on an answer choice if you would like to remove it. This question is worth 2 points.\n\nFruits are mainly used by plants to protect their seeds and can be divided into different types based on their structure.",
      "choices": [
        "A. Fruits can be classified into many different types depending on their shape and size.",
        "B. Flowers play an important role in the life cycle of most plants because they facilitate reproduction.",
        "C. Flowers that are male do not possess female reproductive structures.",
        "D. The structure of a fruit can differ significantly based on minor variations in flower structure.",
        "E. Fruits form in the ovary after the flower has been fertilized by pollen.",
        "F. Evidence shows that fruits have become very different over the years due to selective breeding."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "B",
        "D",
        "F"
      ]
    }
  ]
}